Guide to the Norman Weisberg Photographs 1980s PR 179
New-York Historical Society
Norman Weisberg photographs
1980s
New-York Historical Society
Weisberg, Norman, approximately 1930-
PR 179
4 Linear feet in 2 boxes and 1 flat file
24 panoramic photographs dating from the 1980s, all but one in color, taken by New York photographer Norman Weisberg (born circa 1930). The photographs include sweeping views from the Empire State Building and the "Top of the Rock" observation deck of Rockefeller Center, and panoramas focused on particular sites including Shea Stadium, Fulton Fish Market, Ellis Island, the World Trade Center, and others.
Arrangement
The photographs are listed in the container list in chronological order.
Biographical / Historical
Norman Weisberg, born circa 1930, is a panoramic photographer and publisher now living on Long Island, N.Y. He was editor of the photographic journal "The Panoramic Eye." In creating his images, Weisberg employed a globuscope, a spring loaded camera which exposes the film on a continuous roll, thereby creating images that begin and end with the same reference point.
Conditions Governing Access
For more information on making arrangements to consult the collection, please visit www.nyhistory.org/library/visit.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of the photographer, Norman Weisberg, in 2001 and 2018-2022.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of 24 panoramic prints, each of which is listed in the container list. Generally, the photographs include sweeping views from the Empire State Building and the "Top of the Rock" observation deck of Rockefeller Center, and panoramas focused on particular sites including inside Shea Stadium during the New York Mets' World Series championship year of 1986, Fulton Fish Market, Ellis Island, and the World Trade Center.
All the photos date from the 1980s. All but that of the Fulton Fish Market are in color. The size of the prints varies from about 65 inches in length to about 15 inches in length.
New York (N.Y.) -- Photographs.; Cityscapes (representations); Panoramas (visual works); Ellis Island Immigration Station (N.Y. and N.J.); Empire State Building (New York, N.Y.); Rockefeller Center; Shea Stadium (New York, N.Y.)
- First Selfie, Taken from Old Pan Am Building, circa 1980 (Folder FF-1)
- Ellis Island, 1983 (Folder FF-1)
- #16. Empire State Building, 1983 (Folder FF-1)
  Scope and Contents
  Panoramic northerly view
- View from Empire State Building (northerly), 1983 (Folder FF-1)
- #12. River to River Series, 1983 Summer (Folder FF-1)
  Panoramic view from Empire State Building
- #14.Top of the Rock, 1983 October (Folder FF-1)
  View from Rockefeller Center observation deck.
- [On the deck of the] USS Enterprise, 1983 (Folder FF-1)
- Water Towers, 1983 (Folder FF-1)
- New Citizens Being Sworn in at Ellis Island, 1983 (Folder FF-1)
- Central Park [corner of 5th Avenue and West 59th Street], 1983 (Folder FF-1)
- 100th Anniversary of Brooklyn Bridge, 1983 (Folder FF-1)
- Restaurant/Ice Rink, Rockefeller Center, 1983 (Folder FF-1)
- 2 Rivers from Pan Am Building [northerly view of Manhattan], 1983 (Folder FF-1)
- [World Trade] Towers + Church (Greek, Destroyed 9/11 When Towers Fell), 1984 (Folder FF-1)
- Art for Art's Sake [Metropolitan Museum of Art gallery], 1984 (Folder FF-1)
- From the Rooftop of Rockefeller Center, circa 1985 (Box 2)
- #4. New York City, 1985 (Folder FF-1)
  Appears to be Times Square
- Under B.B. [Brooklyn Bridge]. Bedrock Where Roebling Tread, 1985 (Box 1)
- Sunday on Wall Street, 1986 (Folder FF-1)
- September to Remember at Shea Stadium, 1986 (Box 1)
  Panorama of field and stands from above home plate
- Fulton Fish Market, 1986 (Folder FF-1)
- World Trade Center, 1986 (Folder FF-1)
- #4. Triangle, 1980s (Folder FF-1)
  Panoramic southerly view from Top of the Rock
- View up exterior of lower Manhattan building, 1980s (Folder FF-1)